Inventory of the Howard A. Reed papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file (Folder 24-27)
  - Public Law (PL) 480, Library of Congress, 1964-1965 (Folder 27: 9)
  - Caradon, Lord, 1979 (Folder 27: 10)
    Inlcudes 2 compact cassette tapes
  - Congressional committees, undated (Folder 27: 11)
  - Davis DuBois, Rachel, 1972 (Folder 27: 12)
  - Ditchley conference paper, undated (Folder 27: 13)
  - Egan, Mark, 1972 (Folder 27: 14)
  - Fine, James, 1979 (Folder 27: 15)
  - Gallagher, Charles, 1979 (Folder 27: 16)
  - Harfford Seminary literature, 1982 (Folder 27: 17)
  - Toueir, Kassem, 1980 (Folder 27: 18)
- Notes on telephone conversations, 1980 (Folder 27: 19)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 28-38)
  - History Department and Middle East Studies Program (Folder 28-32:)
    - Financial records (Folder 28-29)
      - Budget, 1978-1979 (Folder 28: 1-2)
      - Travel account, 1979-1980 (Folder 28: 3)
      - Payment vouchers, 1978-1980 (Folder 28: 4-5)
      - Payment vouchers, 1978-1980 (Folder 29: 1-2)
      - Payment vouchers, 1980-1981 (Folder 29: 3-4)
      - Complete budget, 1979-1980 (Folder 29: 5-6)
    - Turkey, Turkish education, and Middle East Studies conference, 1980-1983 (Folder 30)
      Includes speeches and writings by Reed
    - Middle East Institute conference materials, 1981 (Folder 31: 1)
    - Newsletters, journals, and other printed matter relating to Turkey and the Middle East, 1980-1981 (Folder 31: 2-3)
    - Institute of Social Studies (Netherlands) course calendars, 1966-1968 (Folder 31: 4-5)
    - Fernea, Elizabeth, 1979 (Folder 31: 6)
    - Basheer, Tahseen, 1976-1980 (Folder 31: 7)
    - Learning Resources Center reports on Egypt, 1976-1977 (Folder 31: 8)
    - Faculty workload analysis, 1976 (Folder 32: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Folder 32: 2)
    - Conferences, seminars, and other meetings relating to Middle East studies, 1974-1981 (Folder 32: 3)
    - International studies and study abroad printed matter, 1980 (Folder 32: 4-5)
    - Friends World College, 1982-1989 (Folder 32: 6)
  - International studies and study abroad printed matter, 1980 (Folder 33: 1)
    Mostly published by the Learning Resources in International Studies program for the ISA Consortium for International Studies Education
  - Catalog of Asian studies resources in Connecticut and related materials, 1980 (Folder 33: 2)
  - International Implications of the Energy Crisis conference materials, 1980 (Folder 33: 3)
  - Higher education in Egypt, 1975-1977 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Middle East Studies Group (Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, notes, and other materials relating to education in Egypt and Saudi Arabia, 1976-1977 (Folder 34: 1-2)
  - Middle East Studies Committee report on Middle East Studies Center, undated (Folder 34: 3)
  - Collected reports and studies relating to international education, 1967 (Folder 34: 4)
    Mostly relates to India
  - Seminar on Latin America booklet, published by State of Tennessee Department of Education, 1967 (Folder 34: 5)
  - Conferences and meetings (Folder 35)
    - Slavic Conference, 1981 (Folder 35: 1)
    - Global 2000 Conference, 1981 (Folder 35: 2)
    - Mobile Outreach workshop, Farmington meeting, 1980 September (Folder 35: 3)
    - Middle East Studies Association workshop report, "Cooperation Among Middle East Libraries of North America,", 1975 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Middle East Studies publicity, 1981 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Internal Revenue Service correspondence, 1981 (Folder 35: 6)
  - Congressional bills relating to education, 1965 (Folder 35: 7)
  - Hamline University Faculty Institute on Africa and Faculty Institute on the Middle East, 1964-1965 (Folder 35: 8)
  - Syllabi for Middle East studies courses taught by J. C. Hurewitz, 1967-1968 (Folder 35: 9)
  - Printed matter (Folder 35)
    - Report of the United States Advisory Commission on Public Democracy, 1982 (Folder 35: 10)
    - Helmer, Olaf, et al. "Development of Long-Range Forecasting Methods for Connecticut: A Summary,", 1969 (Folder 35: 11)
  - Brochures, booklets, and other printed matter published by educational associations, including the American Council on Education, 1979-1980 (Folder 36)
  - Project Learn, 1979-1980 (Folder 37: 1)
  - Yale University, 1980 (Folder 37: 2)
  - Directory of International Education, University of Connecticut, 1980 (Folder 37: 3)
  - North Shore Community College and Massachusetts Consortium, 1979-1980 (Folder 37: 4)
  - "International Education Studies Program" at Mount Hood Community College, 1979 (Folder 37: 5)
  - Office of International Education Development (OIED) newsletter and related correspondence, 1980-1981 (Folder 37: 6)
  - International Studies Association (ISA) materials, 1980-1981 (Folder 37: 7-12)
  - International Studies Association (ISA) materials, 1980 (Folder 38: 1)
  - Undergraduate International Studies Program flyer and related materials, 1979-1980 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Center for Latin American Studies, 1980-1981 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Informational file on organizations, programs, and schools related to international education, 1980 (Folder 38: 4-6)
- Subject file (Folder 39-47)
  - Resumes, 1969-1970 (Folder 39: 1)
  - Retired Foreign Service Officers Association, undated (Folder 39: 2)
  - Retired Officers Association, undated (Folder 39: 3)
  - Rhodes Scholarship, 1965 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Riggs, F. Behn, Jr., 1967 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Roberts, Preston T., Jr., 1951-1967 (Folder 39: 6)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1972 (Folder 39: 7)
  - Rollins College, 1964 (Folder 39: 8)
  - Rose, Mrs. C., 1971 (Folder 39: 9)
  - Rutgers University, 1964 (Folder 39: 10)
  - S, 1971 (Folder 39: 11)
  - St. Mary's University, San Antonio, Texas, 1970 (Folder 39: 12)
  - Saturday Review, 1966-1970 (Folder 39: 13)
  - San Francisco State University, 1965 (Folder 39: 14)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1975-1976 (Folder 39: 15)
  - Scandinavia seminar, 1969-1972 (Folder 39: 16)
  - Schachter, Gustav, 1970 (Folder 39: 17)
  - Schertz, Lyle, 1971 (Folder 39: 18)
  - "School and Society,", 1965 (Folder 39: 19)
  - School boards, 1965 (Folder 39: 20)
  - Schroeder, Peter B., undated (Folder 39: 21)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1965 (Folder 39: 22)
  - Schultz, T. W., undated (Folder 39: 23)
  - Science, 1964 (Folder 39: 24)
  - Scribner's [Charles] Sons, 1971 (Folder 39: 25)
  - Secondary education, 1963 (Folder 40: 1)
  - Shri Padmarathi Women's College of Shrivenkateswara University, Tiriypati, India, undated (Folder 40: 2)
  - Singer, Milton, undated (Folder 40: 3)
  - Singer, Morris, 1969 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Slavic and Eastern European Studies Center, 1977 (Folder 40: 5)
  - Slottman, William Bradley, 1969 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Smart, Reginald, 1968 (Folder 40: 7)
  - Smithsonian Institute, 1967-1970 (Folder 40: 8)
  - Social Sciences and Humanities Center, Columbia University, 1966 (Folder 40: 9)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1949 (Folder 40: 10)
  - Social Sciences Research Overseas, 1965-1966 (Folder 40: 11)
  - Society for Higher Education newsletters, 1967-1969 (Folder 40: 12)
  - Society for the Family of Man, 1965 (Folder 40: 13)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education, 1965-1970 (Folder 40: 14)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education, 1965-1970 (Contd.) (Folder 41: 1)
  - Society for Scientific Study of Religion, 1971 (Folder 41: 2)
  - Sonoma State College, 1971 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Sophia University, 1965-1966 (Folder 41: 4)
  - South Florida, University of, 1964 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1964 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Speakers' topics, 1968 (Folder 41: 7)
  - State Department (Folder 41)
    - Aid, 1964 (Folder 41: 8)
    - Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, 1963 (Folder 41: 9)
    - Education, 1973 (Folder 41: 10)
    - External research staff, 1964-1965 (Folder 41: 11)
    - High school project, undated (Folder 41: 12)
    - Public affairs, 1964 (Folder 41: 13)
    - Public services, 1966 (Folder 41: 14)
    - Scholar-diplomats, 1972 (Folder 41: 15)
  - State Executive Committee, 1971 (Folder 41: 16)
  - Stavrianos, Leften, 1965 (Folder 41: 17)
  - Stevenson (Adelai) Memorial, 1965-1971 (Folder 41: 18)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang, undated (Folder 41: 19)
  - Student aid newsletter, 1968 (Folder 41: 20)
  - Students, 1964-1966 (Folder 41: 21)
  - Study and teaching abroad, 1962-1965 (Folder 41: 22)
  - Success Unlimited, 1969 (Folder 41: 23)
  - Study and teaching abroad, 1962-1965 (Folder 41: 24)
  - Suwwan, Mahmud. "Design for Manpower Planning in Underdeveloped Countries," dissertation, 1968 (Folder 41: 23)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) (Folder 42)
    - Binghampton, 1972 (Folder 42: 1)
    - Harpur College Southwest Asian and North African studies (SWANA) project, 1965 (Folder 42: 2)
    - Oyster Bay, 1966 (Folder 42: 3)
    - Plattsburgh, 1962-1965 (Folder 42: 4)
  - Sudan, 1971 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Survey of International Development, 1965 (Folder 42: 6)
  - Swarthmore College, 1965 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Swartz, Merlin, 1970 (Folder 42: 8)
  - Szyliowicz, Joseph S. (University of Denver), 1967 (Folder 42: 9)
  - Tabb, William K., 1969 (Folder 42: 10)
  - Tachau, Frank, 1959 (Folder 42: 11)
  - Taiwan proposal, 1966 (Folder 42: 12)
  - Taylor, Harold, 1966 (Folder 42: 13)
  - Teacher's College, Columbia University, 1965-1966 (Folder 42: 14)
  - Teacher training, 1962-1965 (Folder 42: 15)
  - Television education, undated (Folder 42: 16)
  - Temple, New Hampshire, 1964 (Folder 42: 17)
  - Temple of Understanding, 1968-1970 (Folder 42: 18)
  - Thayer Academy, 1962-1963 (Folder 42: 19)
  - Theological study, 1965-1966 (Folder 42: 20)
  - Threshold, University of Connecticut newsletter, 1973 (Folder 42: 21)
  - Tropical Studies organization, 1971 (Folder 42: 22)
  - Turkey, 1971 (Folder 42-43)
    - General research materials and correspondence, 1958-1971 (Folder 42: 23)
    - AID Turkey, 1972 (Folder 42: 24)
    - American Research Institute in Turkey, 1971-1973 (Folder 42: 25)
    - American Research Institute in Turkey, 1971-1973 (Contd.) (Folder 43: 1)
    - Agriculture, 1965-1971 (Folder 43: 2)
    - Turkey-America Board, 1971 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Turner, Frederick, 1967-1968 (Folder 43: 4)
  - Typewriter, 1970 (Folder 43: 5)
  - Tyrrell, Philip H., 1964 (Folder 43: 6)
  - U. E. Advisory Committee, 1964-1965 (Folder 43: 7)
  - Ulrich, Ivan, 1971 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Union for Experimenting Colleges and Universities, 1973 (Folder 43: 9)
  - Union for Research and Experimentation in Higher Education, 1968 (Folder 43: 10)
  - United Arab Republic, 1964 (Folder 43: 11)
  - United Church Board for World Ministries, 1966-1969 (Folder 43: 12)
  - United Nations, 1964-1965 (Folder 43: 13)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1964-1969 (Folder 43: 14)
  - United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR), 1966 (Folder 43: 15)
  - United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund (UNICEF), 1965 (Folder 43: 16)
  - United Nations Quaker program, 1967-1970 (Folder 43: 16)
  - United States budget, 1965 (Folder 43: 17)
  - University of California Los Angeles Student Counseling Services, 1968 (Folder 43: 18)
  - Unver, Altan, 1969 (Folder 43: 19)
  - Butts, R. Freeman, 1981 (Folder 44: 1)
  - Ciller, Tansu, 1972 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Cohn, Edwin J., 1966-1967 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Committee on New Alternatives in the Middle East (CONAME), 1973 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Compton, Randolph P., 1964 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Education and World Affairs (EWA), 1964-1970 (Folder 44: 6-8)
  - Esenbel, Melih (ambassador to Turkey), 1973 (Folder 44: 9)
  - Faculty meetings, undated (Folder 44: 10)
  - Faculty seminar, Barrington Moore's book, 1968-1984 (Folder 44: 11)
  - Faksh, Mahmud, 1976-1977 (Folder 44: 12)
  - Fersh, Seymour H. "Studying Other Cultures: Looking Outward in 'In'", undated (Folder 44: 13)
  - Foreign languages, 1970 (Folder 44: 14)
  - Friends World College, 1964-1965 (Folder 44: 15)
  - Friends World Institute, 1967-1968 (Folder 44: 16)
  - Fulbright-Hays research grant, 1966-1978 (Folder 44: 17-18)
  - Fulbright-Hays research grant, 1970-1977 (Folder 45: 1-2)
  - Fulbright-Hays senior program. Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1970 (Folder 45: 3)
  - G, 1971 (Folder 45: 4)
  - Ghandi, 1969 (Folder 45: 5)
  - Gerçek, 1970 (Folder 45: 6)
  - Greece, 1962 (Folder 45: 7)
  - Gregorian, Vartan, 1973 (Folder 45: 8)
  - Gugler, 1971 (Folder 45: 9)
  - Hartford Seminary Foundation, 1978 (Folder 45: 10)
  - Haverford College Center for Nonviolent Conflict Resolution, 1970-, 1970-1971 (Folder 45: 11)
  - Hook, Judith, 1973 (Folder 45: 12)
  - International Business Machines (IBM), 1966 (Folder 45: 13)
  - Institute of International and Intercultural Studies (IIIS), University of Connecticut, 1965-1973 (Folder 45: 14-16)
  - Institute of International and Intercultural Studies (IIIS), University of Connecticut, budget files, 1967-1969 (Folder 46: 1-2)
  - International Studies of Values in Politics (Phil Jacob), 1966 (Folder 46: 3)
  - Interdepartmental, 1971 (Folder 46: 4)
  - Japan, 1964-1966 (Folder 46: 5)
  - Libya, 1964 (Folder 46: 6)
  - Lisle Fellowship Inc., 1968 (Folder 46: 7-8)
  - Malenbaum, Wilfred, 1960 (Folder 46: 9)
  - Middle East Journal, 1977 (Folder 46: 10)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, Israel, and Middle East studies, 1977-1987 (Folder 47: 1)
- Transcripts of statements by Yehuda Z. Blum to the United Nations, 1980 (Folder 47: 2)
- United Nations bulletins and reports on Palestinian rights, 1978-1980 (Folder 47: 3)
- Palestine Human Rights Campaign materials, 1979-1980 (Folder 47: 4)
- Malhuret, Claude. "Mass Deportations in Ethiopia," Doctors Without Borders report, 1985-1986 (Folder 47: 5)
- "Perspectives on the Islamic World" conference materials, 1987-1988 (Folder 47: 6)
- Master Plan for Higher Education in Connecticut 1974-1977 (Folder 47: 7)
- Informational pamphlet on Turkey published by the Turkish Embassy, undated (Folder 47: 8)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 48-62)
  - Undergraduate International Studies Mobile Outreach Program, 1979 (Folder 48: 1-8)
  - University correspondence, 1978-1981 (Folder 48-50)
    - A, 1979 (Folder 48: 9)
    - B, 1980 (Folder 48: 10)
    - C, 1978-1979 (Folder 49: 1)
    - D, 1980-1981 (Folder 49: 2)
    - E, 1979 (Folder 49: 3)
    - Elias, Julius (Dean), 1978-1980 (Folder 49: 4)
    - F, 1978-1980 (Folder 49: 5)
    - G, 1980-1981 (Folder 49: 6)
    - H, 1978-1981 (Folder 49: 7)
    - I, 1981 (Folder 49: 8)
    - J, 1980 (Folder 49: 9)
    - K, 1978-1981 (Folder 49: 10)
    - L, 1978-1980 (Folder 49: 11)
    - Long, Richard P., 1978 (Folder 49: 12)
    - M, 1979 (Folder 49: 13)
    - N, 1978-1981 (Folder 49: 14)
    - O, 1978-1979 (Folder 49: 15)
    - P, 1979 (Folder 49: 16)
    - Q, undated (Folder 49: 17)
    - R, 1979 (Folder 50: 1)
    - S, 1979 (Folder 50: 2)
    - T, 1979 (Folder 50: 3)
    - U, 1978-1980 (Folder 50: 4)
    - V, 1979-1981 (Folder 50: 5)
    - W, 1979-1980 (Folder 50: 6-7)
    - Wilson, Kenneth G., (Vice president), 1978-1979 (Folder 50: 8)
    - Y, 1979-1981 (Folder 50: 9)
    - University memoranda, 1978 (Folder 50: 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981 Spring (Folder 50: 11)
  - State colleges correspondence, 1978-1981 (Folder 51)
    - A, 1979-1980 (Folder 51: 1)
    - B, 1979-1981 (Folder 51: 2)
    - F, 1979-1980 (Folder 51: 3)
    - P, 1979-1980 (Folder 51: 4)
    - R, 1979-1980 (Folder 51: 5)
    - S, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 6)
    - Shin, Young Gak, 1980 (Folder 51: 7)
    - T, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 8)
    - U, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 9)
    - V, 1980 (Folder 51: 10)
    - W, 1979-1980 (Folder 51: 11)
  - State Colleges Committee on International Studies, 1978 (Folder 51: 12)
  - Undergraduate International Studies Program, 1978-1979 (Folder 51-53)
    - General budget and background materials, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 13)
    - Annual report background materials, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 14)
    - Personnel files, A-M, 1978-1979 (Folder 52:)
      Includes resumes and correspondence
    - Personnel files, N-Z, 1978-1979 (Folder 53:)
      Includes resumes and correspondence. Also includes biographical data on Howard A. Reed
  - Informational materials, including correspondence, announcements, and clippings relating to Middle East Studies and the Middle East Studies Council at the University of Connecticut, 1979 (Folder 54)
    Also includes curricula vitae of research assistants and professors
  - U.S. Office of Education grant renewal documents, 1979 (Folder 55)
    Includes program narratives
  - U.S. Office of Education grant renewal documents, 1979 (Folder 56)
  - U.S. Office of Education grant renewal documents, 1977-1981 (Folder 57)
  - U.S. Office of Education grant renewal documents, 1979 (Folder 58: 1-8)
    Includes budget, final report drafts, and program narrative
  - Correspondence (Folder 58:)
    - K, 1978-1980 (Folder 58: 9)
    - L, 1978-1980 (Folder 58: 10)
    - M, 1980 (Folder 58: 11)
  - Middle East Studies Colloquium reports, 1979-1980 (Folder 58: 12)
  - Memoranda to Middle East Studies Colloquium committee, 1979 (Folder 58: 13)
  - Fundraising materials, 1973-1979 (Folder 58: 14)
  - Printed matter (Folder 59-61)
    - Center for Contemporart Arab Studies, Georgetown University newsletters, 1983-1985 (Folder 59: 1)
    - Center for Middle Eastern Studies, University of California Berkeley newsletters, undated (Folder 59: 2)
    - Center for Near Eastern and North African Studies newsletters, 1984-1986 (Folder 59: 3)
    - Contemporary Mideast Backgrounder, 1979-1987 (Folder 59: 4)
    - Collected materials on Egypt, 1979 (Folder 59: 5)
    - Jebhe, newspaper, 1984 (Folder 59: 6)
    - Kayhan, newspaper, 1986 (Folder 59: 7)
    - Lebanon News, 1984-1987 (Folder 59: 8)
    - "Newsletter of the Task Force on Christian-Muslim Relations,", 1984 (Folder 59: 9)
    - Syria. Department of State Background Notes, undated (Folder 59: 10)
    - Washington Reports on Middle East Affairs, 1982-1984 (Folder 59: 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 59: 12)
    - Directories and catalogs of universities, research foundations, and education associations, 1945-1988 (Folder 60)
    - Directories and catalogs of universities, research foundations, and education associations, 1952-1972 (Folder 61)
    - University of the State of New York/State Education Department Foreign Area Materials Center publications, 1965-1966 (Folder 61)
    - Becker, James M. "An Examination of Objectives, Needs and Priorities in International Education in the U.S. Secondary and Elementary Schools," final report for the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969 July (Folder 61)
    - Blair, Calvin, et al. "Responsibilities of the Foreign Scholar to the Local Scholarly Community: Studies of U.S. Research in Guatemala, Chile, and Paraguay," The Council on Educational Cooperation with Latin America, Education and World Affairs, 1969 (Folder 61)
    - "A Report on the Baccalaureate Origins of College Faculties,", 1959; 1961 (Folder 61)
    - Report on faculty salaries at the University of Connecticut, 1972; 1974 (Folder 61)
    - Associated Student Government Course Critique, 1968 (Folder 61)
  - Undergraduate International Studies program narrative, 1976 (Folder 62: 1)
  - Reports and other papers relating to the International Education Act, 1967 (Folder 62: 2)
  - Courses in India, 1964 (Folder 62: 3)
  - Institute of Turkish Studies proposal, 1982 (Folder 62: 4-5)
  - Directories for Connecticut community colleges, 1978 (Folder 62: 6)
- Subject file (Folder 62-64)
  - Center for World Studies and Human Resource Development office procedures manual, undated (Folder 62: 7)
  - University of Michigan Near and Middle Eastern language program, 1965 (Folder 62: 8)
  - Saturday Review magazine, 1968 (Folder 62: 9)
  - Arab-Israeli relations, 1971-1977 (Folder 63: 1)
  - Breese, William, 1963-1965 (Folder 63: 2)
  - Central Connecticut State College, 1976 (Folder 63: 3)
  - Chambers, Richard L., 1970 (Folder 63: 4)
  - Printed matter, 1971-1981 (Folder 63: 5)
  - Middle East and International Studies, 1967-1988 (Folder 63: 6)
  - Oman, 1975-1976 (Folder 63: 7)
  - Course materials for HIST 205, 1979-1980 (Folder 63: 8-9)
    Relates to Middle East politics
  - Islamic Council of New England conference materials, 1988 (Folder 63: 10)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare grant application documents, 1982 (Folder 63: 11)
  - Middle East bibliographies, 1966-1970 (Folder 63: 12)
  - "First Report of the Non-Western Studies Committee to the Committee of Unit Deans and to the Academic Council of John Carroll University,", 1965 November (Folder 63: 13)
  - I. N. Thut World Education Center, 1985 (Folder 64: 1)
  - World Military and Social Expenditures, 1976; 1979 (Folder 64: 2)
  - Education in the Middle East, 1964-1966 (Folder 64: 3)
  - Middle East Studies Group, 1986 (Folder 64: 4)
  - American Research Center in Egypt, 1971 (Folder 64: 5)
  - American Research Institute in Turkey, 1977 (Folder 64: 6)
  - American University of Beirut, financial brochure, undated (Folder 64: 7)
  - Arabic, 1977 (Folder 64: 8)
  - Arabic language courses, 1976-1977 (Folder 64: 9)
  - Aramco, 1988 (Folder 64: 10)
  - Aspen Institute, 1980 (Folder 64: 11)
  - Association of American Colleges, undated (Folder 64: 12)
  - Atatrk University, 1969 (Folder 64: 13)
  - DeBary, William Theodore, 1964 (Folder 64: 14)
  - Beeley, Brian, 1984 (Folder 64: 15)
  - Benedict, Peter, 1968-1976 (Folder 64: 16)
  - Institute of Development Studies, 1977 (Folder 64: 17)
  - Katz, Milton, 1959 (Folder 64: 18)
  - Middle East Studies--Palestine, 1979-1980 (Folder 64: 19)
  - Vietnam, 1967 (Folder 64: 20)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 64)
  - Budget, 1973 (Folder 64: 21)
  - Candidates for Middle East/Islamic History position, 1988 (Folder 64: 22)
  - Middle East Studies program, 1980-1983 (Folder 64: 23)
- The Turkish Economy 1987 (Folder 64: 24)
- American Friends of the Middle East publicatin series profiling different countries in the Middle East, 1969 (Folder 65)
- "Survey on the Present State and Potentials for Future Development of Management Educations in Turkey," volumes 1-4, 1973 (Folder 65)
- Paper presented at the Middle East Studies Association conference, Toronto, 1969 (Folder 65)
- Teaching--Keller plan, 1972-1973 (Folder 65)
- Middle East Studies Association file (Folder 66)
  - Correspondence and background materials (Folder 66)
    - 1967 (Folder 66: 1)
    - 1968 (Folder 66: 2)
    - 1969 (Folder 66: 3)
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 66: 4)
  - Conferences (Folder 66)
    - Austin, Texas, 1968 (Folder 66: 5-6)
    - Toronto, Canada, 1969 (Folder 66: 7)
  - Middle East program application for funds, 1969 (Folder 66: 8-9)
  - Middle East Airlines Airliban, undated (Folder 66: 10)
  - The Middle East News Review, 1972 (Folder 66: 11)
- Printed matter (Folder 67)
  - Catalogs, directories, and other pamphlets published by different foundations and universities relating to peace research, 1965-1986 (Folder 67)
  - Israel and Palestine Monthly Review, 1978 (Folder 67)
- Ziegler, Warren L. "A Mindbook of Exercises for Futures-Invention,", 1982 (Folder 68: 1)
- University of California, Berkeley Center for Middle East Studies newsletters, 1981 (Folder 68: 2)
- International College, Beirut, Lebanon yearbook, 1980 (Folder 68: 3)
- Friends World College, 1977-1987 (Folder 68: 4)
- Palestine Human Rights Bulletin and related publications, 1978-1980 (Folder 68: 5)
- Copies of newspaper articles on government spending, 1978 (Folder 68: 6)
- Interns for Peace, 1979 (Folder 68: 7)
- University of Connecticut file (Folder 68-70)
  - Middle East Studies Council. Schimmel, Annemarie, 1982 (Folder 68: 8)
  - Daily log, 1978 September (Folder 68: 9)
  - Directories and reference materials, 1981-1984 (Folder 68: 10)
  - USOE Undergraduate International Studies Program budget, 1977-1978 (Folder 68: 11)
  - University correspondence (Folder 69)